# Dara Anya

# Houdini FX Artist

Email: daraanya@gmail.com Phone: +1(713)367-4871 Reel: https://vimeo.com/915364834 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dara-anya ArtStation: https://www.artstation.com/dara-anya GitHub: https://github.com/dara-anya

# Summary

An experienced Houdini FX Artist, with managerial skills, who is educated and has worked in the fields of neuroscience, computer science, film, game production, animation, visual effects and virtual production. FX Artistry resonates with me as the coalescence of science, art and technology: an appreciation of life and the imagination and wonder to expand beyond reality. Let us wonder together.

# Work Experience

#### Houdini FX Artist at Goodman Brothers

Jan. 2024 - Jan. 2024

- · Researched and Developed vellumFX for parade float bursting confetti in Kayo Sports "Get On Board" commercial
- · Implemented feedback and submitted deliverables punctually
- · Collaborated with VFX Supervisors

#### Houdini FX Artist at Spruce Digital

July 2023 - Sept. 2023

- · Created waterFX for tire splash in Big O Tires commercial; researched and developed other shots
- · Constructed timeline and shot breakdowns
- Implemented feedback and submitted deliverables punctually

## Houdini FX Artist at Impossible Objects

March 2023 - May 2023

- · Created vellumFX for shoe reveal in Merrell "Skyfire 2" commercial
- · Researched and Developed waterFX for beach scene in "Better Never Stops" Onstar commercial
- Implemented feedback, submitted deliverables punctually and updated FTrack

## Motion Capture Cleanup Technician/Animator at Motion Capture Orlando

July 2022 - Sept. 2022

- · Cleaned, animated and supervised over 10 mocap sequences for Reallusion's "Run for Your Life" pack
- Initialized motion capture Vicon system and marked performers
- · Liaised with CEO and updated ShotGrid to deliver sequences punctually

# Web Developer/Project Manager at Resicom, Inc.

May 2018 - July 2022

- Improved web design and updated project information
- Managed a \$300,000 City of Houston Clearing and Grubbing project
- · Archived files and updated architectural plans for over six projects

## Content Project Manager at HEADCASE

Sept. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- · Formed, developed and expanded business-client relations
- Composed call sheets, shot lists, set-up and operated equipment and performed other production tasks, as needed
- · Completed and released projects for clients including Vodafone X, Renault, Mind Over Matter and Irish Distillers

## Quality Assurance Supervisor/Compatibility Tester at Aspyr Media

July 2016 - Feb. 2018

- Performed certification sweeps and shipped over seven games including Mafia III and Civilization VI
- · Conducted and pitched concepts at stand-up meetings
- · Tested game functionality on combinations of hardware and software including Linux, Windows and OS systems

# Research Experience

# MEG Brain Scanning Technician Assistant at Dell Children's Medical Center Foundation

June 2016 - Aug. 2016

- · Conducted research to localize the onset of epileptic seizures in humans using MEG brain scanning
- · Programmed and executed experiments using Stim2
- · Reviewed, critiqued and analyzed data from academic research materials

## Research Assistant in Cognitive Psychology Lab at The University of Texas at Austin

Sept. 2012 - Dec. 2015

- Researched cognitive and translational neuroscience of decision making and category learning in humans using fMRI and EEG brain scanning
- Programmed experiments using Python and MATLAB (FSL View used for data analysis)
- · Reviewed and critiqued academic research materials

## Research Assistant in Neuromuscular and Biomechanics Lab at The University of Houston

June 2014 - Aug. 2014

- Researched human ambulation under controlled stress using motion capture units, Vicon camera systems, force plates, loading cells, inertial measurement unit and video capture
- · Reviewed, proposed and critiqued academic research papers
- · Organized and analyzed data

# Education

#### Certificate in Visual Effects

Jan 2022 - Dec. 2022

The Digital Animation & Visual Effects (DAVE) School

#### Bachelor of Science in Neuroscience

Aug. 2012 - May 2016

The University of Texas at Austin

# **Certifications**

#### Certificate in Supervised Machine Learning

Jan. 2024 - Jan. 2024

Stanford University

#### Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development

Feb. 2018 - Feb. 2019

The University of Texas at Austin

## Certificate in Elements of Computing in Python

Jan. 2013 - May 2016

The University of Texas at Austin

# Volunteering

Student Volunteer Dec. 2023 - Dec. 2023

Special Interest Group for Computer Graphics and Interactive Techniques (SIGGRAPH) Asia

Student Volunteer Aug. 2023 - Aug. 2023

Special Interest Group for Computer Graphics and Interactive Techniques (SIGGRAPH)

# Sofware

# **Programming Languages**

# Skills

- Houdini
- Unreal
- Nuke
- Maya
- VICON
- Shogun
- iClone8
- Photoshop
- Substance

- Houdini VEX
- Python
- Java
- JS/HTML/CSS

# Hobbies

- Swimming
- Hiking
- Baking
- Music
- Reading and Writing

- Houdini FX: Flip, Pyro, Vellum, RBD, Muscles, Grooming, etc.
- Houdini Digital Assets Creation
- Real-time FX: UE Niagara
- · Real-time (Virtual) Production
- Pipeline Development: USD, Solaris, MaterialX, Metahumans
- Machine Learning
- · Motion Capture
- Rigging/Animating
- Lighting/Compositing
- Research Development
- Critical and Creative Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Communication
- · Project Management

# Referees

Michael Keith - Director of Career Services, The DAVE School, MKeith@daveschool.com
Joyce Cox - Producer & VFX Consultant, Zu2, Inc., zu2jmc@me.com
Luc Delamare - Head of Technology, Impossible Objects, luc@impossible-objects.com
Morgan McDermott - Head of VFX, Impossible Objects, morgan@impossible-objects.co
PJ Salamon - Lead VFX Instructor, The DAVE School, psalamon@daveschool.com